In this video we're going to generate code for a small example program. The program
在这段视频中，我们将为一个小示例程序生成代码。该计划
we'll take a look at takes a positive imaginary X and sums all the numbers from
我们将看一下，取一个正的虚数X，然后将所有数字相加
O up to X. So if X is O then the result is O. Otherwise it is X plus the sum of all
直到X，所以如果X是O，那么结果是O，否则就是X加上所有的和。
the numbers up to X minus one. So this isn't a interesting program but it does
数字一直到X减1。这不是一个有趣的程序，但它确实很有趣
illustration all of the features that we discuss in the previous couple of videos.
说明我们在前面几个视频中讨论的所有功能。
So let's dive right in and talk about how we're going to generate code for sum two.
那么让我们直接开始，讨论一下如何生成求和2的代码。
So we begin by giving it a label for the entry point to the function, so that'll be
所以我们首先给它一个函数入口点的标签，所以这将是
the sum two entries. Alright and now we have to generate code for the caller's
总和为两个分录。好的，现在我们必须为调用者的
side, call, callee side excuse me, of the calling sequence. So what was that? So the
呼叫顺序的一侧，呼叫方，被呼叫方打扰一下。那是怎么回事？因此，
first thing we have to do is we have to set up the frame pointer, which would just
我们要做的第一件事是设置帧指针，这将只是
be the value of the stack pointer. So that's the frame pointer for this
是堆栈指针的值。这就是这个的帧指针
activation, and. Then we're going to have to store the return address at the current
激活，以及。那么我们将不得不将返回地址存储在当前
value of the stack pointer. And then we're going to move the stack pointer
堆栈指针的值。然后我们要移动堆栈指针
into the - Whenever we store something on the stack we have to move the stack
放入-每当我们在堆栈上存储一些东西时，我们就必须移动堆栈
pointer to the next unused location.  Alright. Okay And so now we have to
指向下一个未使用位置的指针。好的。好的，所以现在我们必须
generate code, for this if then else All right? And the very first thing if you go
为这个生成代码，如果这样，那么其他都可以吗？如果你去的第一件事
back and look at the code for if then else is to generate code for the first sub
返回并查看If Then Else将为第一个SUB生成代码的代码
expression of the predicate. So we're going to generate code for X, and that's
谓词的表达式。所以我们要为X生成代码，这就是
really easy And we're generating code for a variable, just looks up the variable in
非常简单，我们正在为一个变量生成代码，只需在
the current position of the frame. Sorry, at the correct offset from the frame
框架的当前位置。对不起，在距相框的正确偏移处
pointer, alright? Alright so once we do that now we are generating code for the
指针，好吗？好的，一旦我们这样做了，现在我们就为
predicate And how do we do that? Well we generate code for this first sub
谓词，我们该怎么做呢？我们为第一个SUB生成代码
expression, and now we have to save that sub expression somewhere Because we are
表达式，现在我们必须将该子表达式保存在某个位置，因为我们
going to generate code for another sub expression. So the equality there is a
将为另一个子表达式生成代码。所以这里的平等是一个
binary operator, so we have to save the value we just computed somewhere on the
二元运算符，所以我们必须将刚刚计算的值保存在
stack Alright? So we'll do that, so we'll st ore the value of a zero on the stack.
史塔克好吗？所以我们会这么做，所以我们会把零的值存储在堆栈上。
And that will involve, as always, moving the side pointer. Okay and now we generate
这将一如既往地涉及到移动侧边指针。好的，现在我们生成
code for the second sub-expression of the predicate. All right, that's also easy.
谓词的第二个子表达式的代码。好的，这也很容易。
That's just load the immediate of the immediate value into the accumulator,
这只是将立即值的立即数加载到累加器中，
alright. And now I'm going to load the value that we said, the first or we move
好的。现在我要加载我们说过的值，要么第一个，要么我们移动
the predicate back into a temporary register and actually do the comparison.
将谓词放回临时寄存器中，并实际执行比较。
So this is more code, as actually part of the conditional, alright, so we do a load
这是更多的代码，实际上是条件的一部分，好的，所以我们加载
word Entity one Of the value that we saved before. Okay and now we need to pop the
Word实体是我们之前保存的值之一。好的，现在我们需要弹出
stack okay. We'll do that here because we're done with that value. Alright, and
堆叠好了。我们在这里这样做是因为我们已经完成了那个值。好的，还有
now we're going to do the branch. So now we test whether. The two sub-expressions
现在我们要做的是分支。所以现在我们测试一下。这两个子表达式
of the predicate are equal or not, and if they are, then we jump to the true branch.
的谓词是否相等，如果它们相等，那么我们就跳到真正的分支。
And here I'm going to give the true branch a unique label, because this might be part
在这里，我要给真正的分支一个独特的标签，因为这可能是
of a larger program where there are many if-then-else's, and so I'm going to append
一个更大的程序，其中有许多if-Then-Else，所以我要追加
some identifying number on the end. Instead of writing out true branch, I'll
尾部有一些识别码。我不会写出真正的分支，而是
call this true one Alright? Okay, and then if we fall through, then we're on the
就当这是真的好吗？好的，如果我们失败了，那我们就在
false branch, we'll call that false one And now we're generating code for the
False分支，我们将该分支称为false分支，现在我们正在为
false branch, which is this summation here Alright? And how are we going to do that?
假分支，这里的求和是哪一个？我们要怎么做呢？
Well this, whole thing is a plus expression, which means we have the
嗯，这个，整个事情是一个加号表达式，这意味着我们有
generic code first. For the first sub-expression which is just X. Alright?
首先是泛型代码。对于第一个子表达式，也就是X，好吗？
So what do we do? Well we load. To generate code for x we look up x at its
那我们该怎么做呢？好的，我们装船。为了生成x的代码，我们在x的
current offset. And that is the appropriate offset in the frame, using the
当前偏移量。这是帧中的适当偏移量，使用
frame pointer. Okay? It is the only argument, and so it's at four from the
帧指针。好吧?这是唯一的论点，所以现在是四点。
frame pointer. I'm sorry the only argument to the procedure, and so that's stored at
帧指针。很抱歉，这个过程的唯一参数，所以它存储在
the first position for arguments, which is always four from the frame pointer in our
参数的第一个位置，它始终是从
scheme. All right, and now that we've loaded it we have to save it because it is
计划。好的，现在我们已经加载了它，我们必须保存它，因为它是
part of a binary operation so we're going to save that value on the stack. Kay. And
二进制运算的一部分，所以我们要将该值保存在堆栈上。凯。和
now we will adjust the stack pointer. Okay. And what are we going to do next? Well,
现在我们将调整堆栈指针。好吧。那我们下一步要做什么呢？井,
now we've, we've, we computed this sub-expression, this X. We can't do the
现在我们已经，我们已经，我们计算了这个子表达式，这个X。我们不能
plus yet until we compute the second sub-expression which is the function call
加上，直到我们计算第二个子表达式，即函数调用
Alright? So now we have the generate code for the function call and I'm going to
好吗？现在我们有了函数调用的生成代码，我将
move up here to the other side of the screen here to, to show the rest of the
从这里移到屏幕的另一边，在这里，展示
code. Okay And the first thing we do, to generate code, for the function call Is to
密码。好的，我们要做的第一件事是为函数调用生成代码
start setting up our activation record Alright? This is even setting up the new
开始设置我们的激活记录，好吗？这甚至是在设置新的
activation record for the function, call that we're about to make Alright? So what
函数的激活记录，我们将要进行的调用，好吗？那又怎样
do we do there? We store The frame pointer. 'Kay, use this to our old frame
我们在那里做吗？我们存储帧指针。好的，把这个用在我们的旧相框上
pointer. Add the stack on the stack. [sound] Alright, and now, we have to
指针。将堆栈添加到堆栈上。[声音]好的，现在，我们必须
compute the argument All right? We have to compute the x-1. So that code gets
计算一下这个论点，对吗？我们必须计算x-1。所以代码会得到
inserted here in the template for our function call. So, what's going to happen
在此处插入到我们的函数调用的模板中。那么，接下来会发生什么呢？
there? Well, we're completing subtraction, so the template for subtraction is to
那里?嗯，我们正在完成减法，所以减法的模板是
first generate code for the first sub-expression, then generate code for the
首先为第一个子表达式生成代码，然后为
second sube-xpression, and then subtract them. All right, so let's do that. So,
第二个Sube-Xpression，然后减去它们。好的，那我们就这么做吧。所以,
first we generate code for x again. Okay, and now, since it's the first argument of
首先，我们再次为x生成代码。好的，现在，既然这是
a binary operation, we're going to save it on stack. Alright now we generate code for
一个二元运算，我们要把它保存在堆栈上。好的，现在我们为
the second argument of the subtraction. Okay, and now we perform the subtractions
减法的第二个参数。好的，现在我们来做减法
so we have to load the first argument back into a temporary register. Have to
所以我们必须将第一个参数加载回临时寄存器。不得不
actually do the subtraction. Excuse me here. Alright, and then we can pop the
实际上是做减法。打扰一下。好的，然后我们就可以把
temporary value off the stack. Okay, now we have actually done subtraction. Let me
堆栈外的临时值。好的，现在我们真的做了减法。让我
see that. There is everything, from about here to down there is computing x minus y.
看到了吗。所有的东西，从这里到下面，都是计算x减去y。
Okay... So this is computing x And this was computing one And then this whole
好的..。这是计算x，这是计算1，然后是整个
thing is computing the subtraction Alright? So now we compute the argument.
事情就是计算减法，好吗？所以现在我们来计算这个论点。
What are we going to do? Well we save it on the stack. So now we save the result on
我们该怎么办呢？我们把它保存在堆栈上。所以现在我们将结果保存在
the stack. We're saving it into the new activat ion record that we're building
堆栈。我们要把它保存到我们正在建立的新的激活记录中
Alright? And then we have to advance this, or move the stack pointers as always And
好吗？然后我们必须推进这一步，或者像往常一样移动堆栈指针
now we're ready, we have to do the function calls And now we do the jump in
现在我们准备好了，我们必须进行函数调用，现在我们跳到
the link to the entry point of sum two Okay? And now when this returns, what it's
连接到2和的入口点的链接，好吗？现在当它回来的时候，它是什么
going to return with, it's going to return what the result of computing the sum to in
返回的是，它将返回计算和的结果是
the accumulator, all right? And so then, we're ready to perform the addition And
蓄电池，好吗？然后，我们准备好执行加法和
now we've computed the second argument to the addition and how do we do that? Well,
现在我们已经计算了加法的第二个参数，我们该怎么做呢？井,
look back at the template for addition the next thing what happens is we reload the
回过头来看一下用于添加的模板，接下来会发生的事情是我们重新加载
temporary value that we saved on the stack. Alright and now we got actually
我们保存在堆栈上的临时值。好的，现在我们实际上得到了
perform the edition. Okay? And then we could pop the temporary value of the stack
执行编辑。好吧?然后我们可以弹出堆栈的临时值
Alright And that actually ends the, the else branch, the false branch of the
好的，这实际上结束了，Else分支，False分支
entire if and else And there's now a branch around the rest of the if and else
整个IF和ELSE，现在IF和ELSE的睡觉周围有一个分支
code And we'll call that label if and one And now comes the code for the true
代码，我们将调用该标签If和One，现在是TRUE的代码
branch. And what we are going to put there, well, it's not very complicated
布兰奇。我们要放在那里的东西，嗯，并不是很复杂
because all we're doing true branch is loading or generating codes for zero which
因为我们真正要做的就是为零加载或生成代码，
is a single load immediate, load immediate Alright And that's the entire true branch
是单个立即加载，立即加载好的，那就是整个真分支
and so now we're at um there should not be a colon there excuse me, and in fact I can
所以现在我们在，嗯，不应该有冒号，打扰一下，事实上我可以
just erase that a little bit Alright And now we're at and actually I see it notice
只要把它抹去一点，好的，现在我们到了，实际上我看到它注意到了
in the wrong place so let's fix that so this is a branch at the end of the false
在错误的位置，让我们修正一下，这是False结尾处的一个分支
branch, at the end of the else, part of the if and we're going to, to branch
分支，在ELSE的末尾，IF的一部分，我们要，分支
around per quote for the two branch which is only one instruction. And so the very
在两个分支的每个报价附近，这只是一条指令。所以非常重要的是
next instruction is the label end if. So now what's left to do, we've generated code for the whole if then else so
下一条指令是标签End If。现在剩下要做的是，我们已经为整个If Then Else So生成了代码
now it goes here is the rest of the template for the function definition so
这里是函数定义模板的睡觉，所以
now we have to generate the code returns back to the caller and how do we do well
现在我们必须生成返回给调用者的代码返回，我们该如何做好呢
we have to load the return address The on the stack, okay? And now we pop the stacks
我们得把回邮地址加载到堆栈上，好吗？现在我们把堆栈打开
so we pop the entire activation record off the stack and now because of the
所以我们将整个激活记录从堆栈中弹出，现在因为
activation reco rd well remember, there's always two words. One for the return
激活记录我们要记住，总是有两个词。一张返程票。
address and one for the frame pointer and then a number of words equals to the
地址和一个用于帧指针的字，然后字的数量等于
number of arguments where there's only one argument here, so we have three words, so
这里只有一个参数的参数数量，所以我们有三个单词，所以
it's twelve bytes. So we increment the stack pointer by twelve, all right? And
它是十二个字节。所以我们将堆栈指针递增12，好吗？和
then we load the old frame pointer, we store the frame pointer. Okay, and then we
然后我们加载旧的帧指针，我们存储帧指针。好的，然后我们
return. So, one more instruction, we'll do a jump register to the return address And
回来吧。因此，再执行一条指令，我们将对返回地址执行跳转寄存器
that is the entire code for this simple functions sum2 And there's a couple of
这就是这个简单函数sum2的全部代码，其中有几个
things to point out. So, first of all the, the code is constructed as a bunch of
需要指出的事情。所以，首先，代码被构造为一串
templates pasted together and I try to point out as we go along how that
模板粘贴在一起，我试着在我们进行的过程中指出
works But we do lined up with one linear sequence of code. Alright and if, if
有效，但我们使用的是一个线性代码序列。好的，如果，如果
you're all confused as we work as to go back and look at those templates and look
当我们工作时，你们都很困惑，因为我们要回去看那些模板，然后再看一看
at this example and understand how the code all fits together and how it works.
在这个示例中，了解所有代码是如何组合在一起的，以及它是如何工作的。
And the other thing I would point out is just that this is your extremely
我要指出的另一件事是，这是你的极端
inefficient code so later here where we were generating code to check whether x=0.
低效的代码，所以后面我们生成代码来检查x是否=0。
Notice here that we, we load x so this is a load Of x And then we immediately store
注意，我们，我们加载x，所以这是x的加载，然后我们立即存储
the x again into the stacks, we just loaded it now from the frame then we
再次将x放入堆栈，我们现在只是将其从帧中加载，然后我们
immediately store it back in the memory and then we and load the immediate value
立即将其存储回内存中，然后我们并加载立即值
then we reload the value of x here. So, you know, moving the value of x we you
然后我们在这里重新加载x的值。所以，你知道，移动x的值
know, all around. So we load it, we store it, we load it again and this was a lot of
你知道，到处都是。所以我们加载它，我们存储它，我们再次加载它，这是很多
wasted motion here and that's a result of this very simple cogeneration strategy
这里浪费了运动，这是这个非常简单的热电联产策略的结果
where we want to be able to compose code together. We will be able to compose these
我们希望能够一起编写代码。我们将能够创作出这些
templates in a way that it will work properly. This code does not have to be
模板，以使其能够正常工作。此代码不必是
this inefficient in a lot of the techniques of what we discussed in
这在我们在中讨论的许多技术中都是低效的
sub-sequential lectures we talked about in a smarter code generation techniques and
我们在更智能的代码生成技术和
also optimizations like even improve the code further.
此外，像这样的优化甚至进一步改进了代码。